And now the third of our sizzles is
OpenClaw. Open Claw is massively hyped
at the moment and blowing up and I
personally rather suspect that it's
going to die down a bit. I could be
completely wrong. I might be like
someone that's saying this chat GPT
thing, it's not going to last. But uh
yeah, I I might as well just throw it
into the mix of some sizzle. It's not of
course related to coding agents. It's a
big hyped thing, but just to give you a
sense of what it is, so you got the
context. It is still sort of it's it's
first of all, it was itself vibecoded
and it's very much on on the same theme
of appreciating the power of these
coding agents like claw code and
imagining rather like co-works if we
apply this to everyday beyond
development. And open glor is taking it
even further. It's described as your
personal AI. It's about really trying to
to be your sidekick, something that
could be there for you. And it's also
considered something that's that's a bit
on the dangerous side because you run it
on your computer, you typically give it
access to everything. You connect it to
everything. That's why it has its power.
But with with great power comes
responsibility and and comes risk. And
that's why some security professionals
are very concerned about OpenClaw. And
one way that you could run it, of
course, is in a sandbox as we discovered
a couple of days ago. Anyway, OpenClaw
isn't completely relevant for for coding
except for for seeing the potential of
this stuff. So, I will just quickly give
you a perspective on it so that we we
get our sizzle and then we will move
swiftly on. So, here is OpenClaw and you
go to openclaw.ai to see this page.
which OpenCL of course was originally
called Claudebot spelled C L A W D
Claudebot. Uh and apparently they had a
letter from from Anthropic and so they
changed their name to Maltbot which was
still a sort of riff off this the the
lobster idea. Uh but that they decided
didn't didn't sound it was hard to say
and so they changed it third time to
open claw which is what it's called now
unless it's changes name again but I
doubt it. So open claw is what we've got
and you can install it with a oneliner.
That's the one line for MacOSS. If
you're on a Windows PC, then this would
be your oneliner if you're on a
PowerShell or this in a CMD, but you'll
probably be on a PowerShell. But I'm
going to go back to being on a Mac. And
I will run this now in a terminal. And
one of the things I say is that if you
don't know how to use a terminal, then
perhaps you're not ready to use OpenClaw
because it's it's designed for people
that know enough about what's going on
to feel like you you uh you know the
risks you're signing up for. And of
course, the the main thing as it says
here that that that it runs on your
computer that the way that you interact
with it is through a chat app. It's like
got a this native chat first experience.
You can be in WhatsApp or in Telegram
talking to your sidekick to your
Claudebot. It's got it's got memory. It
remembers what's going on. It can drive
a browser. It can use anything on your
computer. And it's got a whole raft of
plugins that you could click into it.
And therein lies many of its powers. So
here, look, I brought up a terminal.
This is just a normal Mac terminal. I'm
going to paste in that command to
install it on my Mac. Let's give this a
try. It's doing uh doing a bunch of uh
stuff and uh open installer. I'm the
reason your shell history looks like a
hacker movie montage.
Okay. And I will let it do its thing. I
will see you in a sec. And so I love
this. It says uh OpenClaw installed
successfully. The lobster has landed.
Your terminal will never be the same.
Let's make this nice and big for you.
Uh, and then we get this uh, open claw
security. Please read. It's a hobby
project still in beta. Expect sharp
edges. It can read files, run actions. A
bad prompt can trick it to doing unsafe
things. Uh, run an open clause security
audit regularly. You must read the
security stuff. I understand this is
powerful. and inherently risky.
Continue. Defaulting to no, we'll go to
yes. Uh onboarding mode, quick start.
And we will do the quick start. Okay.
And now we get to the models. And we
start with choosing a model orth
provider. And it's got a bunch of them.
And I think we've we've uh we've got
enough of of using anthropic. We let's
switch to OpenAI for a bit and use uh
oorth. So I'm going to select this. uh
we can choose whether we want to do a
chat GPT oorthth or whether we want to
use an API key. This this is like an in
browser login and that is the one that
we will try. So I will do this
and it jumps me over to here. Continue
with Google.
Sign into codeex with chat GBT.
Continue.
That's successful. Return to your
terminal to continue. And now it's
saying default model keep current. We'll
use GPT53 codecs. That sounds good to
me. Select uh channel quick start. So,
I'd say let's go with Telegram. Let's do
Telegram. Telegram bot token. Open
Telegram. And now it's telling me to to
do this. And I have Telegram. So, I'm
going to open Telegram. I'm going to
chat. I'm going to select that I want to
chat with atbotfather. I'm going to run
slash newbot. It's going to make a token
and I'm going to copy it in here. And
then I'm going to keep going and I'm I'm
going to do that offline so that I keep
that that secret and I'll see you back
here in a sec. Okay, so I did that. I
set up my Telegram bar following the
instructions and my ID the the token is
just off the top of the screen. So I
shrunk it down and then I've said yes, I
want to configure skills now. My
preferred node manager is npm and I can
now install skills, different things to
do stuff that might be useful for me.
And you can see all the different things
it can do by scrolling through here and
get a good sense. It could turn on and
off my light bulbs. It could do all
these different things. And let me see
what we want to have it be able to do
today. Okay. So, I've only chosen one
simple skill, the OpenAI whisper, which
seems like a nice easy one. It's got no
API key. It just means that there'll be
access to speech to text. So, we'll let
that install and then we'll uh see what
else we can set up. Okay, so I went
through a setup process. I had to answer
a few questions. It wanted to know what
it would be called, and I called it
psychic. Kind of boring. It wanted to
know a vibe and it wanted an emoji. I'm
definitely not cool enough to be using
this product. So, I tried my best and uh
I then hooked it up to a few things and
now it's connected to Telegram, so I can
chat with it over Telegram. And I could
be doing this on my phone. I could be
doing this as I am on my computer, my
Telegram app. But uh this is going to
allow me now to have a conversation with
my sidekick running on my computer.
Okay, let's give this a try. I'm
pressing start. Let's have a
conversation. I'm here, Edward.
Sidekick's ready. Okay. Uh please look
up Tesla
stock price.
If uh it
um went up today,
please play me something upbeat.
Otherwise, something depressing.
Okay, let's give it that instruction.
I'm wanting it to go and do a web
search. I want it to understand what I
mean, figure this out, and then play me
music. How's it going to do that?
Through Telegram or something?
Okay, we have music. We have something
playing. It went up today. And so it's
playing upside down by Diana Ross. And
how's it playing it? It's playing it
because it's controlling Spotify on my
computer. It's activated Spotify and
it's playing Diana Ross.
And here you can see the telegram uh
chat I was having alongside open claw
that was running on my computer in this
terminal UI looking a lot like clawed
code in a way and it's got a message.
It's replying to it. It's decided it's
looked up the stock price. It went up
today. Upbeat is the decision. It made a
choice about what track to play. I left
that up to its autonomy, its discretion.
It put on Diana Ross. controlled Spotify
and that's what you heard playing. So,
you know that that gives you a sense of
what what this is all about. People are
excited because you can drive things
from just from your your chat interface.
It comes to you. It can it can wake up
and alert you about things. It can be
integrated across all of the
capabilities on your computer. It can
drive Windows. It can look things up on
the web. So, it it can be incredibly
autonomous. And it really brings the
power of Claude code and the CLI tools
again that we're used to as engineers
and it brings them to people personally
as their personal sidekick. Okay, so
that brings today to a wrap. Today
really was a light day. We did cover the
big project concerns of just the right
way to approach a big repo and we will
touch on that again tomorrow when we
when things go really crazy. And then
after doing that, we just had some light
relief with a few things for you to look
at like like the good old Claude agent
SDK, which is which is an important way
to drive claude code programmatically.
And then we looked at co-work taking
what this these exciting tooling and
bringing it to the professional world.
And then open claw which is bringing the
same kind of capability to a personal
world to have everyone have their own
personal sidekick that you could control
from telegram from WhatsApp and have it
be able to control your computer your
lights your music whatever you want and
that that is open claw I know I just
gave you a teaser of it because that's
not really what we're covering on this
course but I did want you to see it and
have a feel for it. All right tomorrow
is a massive day. Tomorrow is when we go
into swarms. We look at teams. We're
going to look at a few really
interesting way to orchestrate multiple
agents collaborating together in unison
to achieve a bigger task. And that will
lead us all the way to the capstone. And
with that, amazingly, 87% is where we're
at. Massive congrats. Get ready for two
big days ahead. See you tomorrow.